Register of the Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals records
Hoover Institution Archives
Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals records
1952-1970
70023
Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals
44 manuscript boxes, 6 envelopes (19 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, financial records, and photographs, relating to relief work for Chinese refugees.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1970.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, financial records, and photographs, relating to relief work for Chinese refugees.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
International relief.; Refugees.; China.; China--History--1949-1976.; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
- Background material on ARCI (Box 1)
- Proposed plans to aid refugee Chinese Intellectuals (correspondence)
- Purpose and program of ARCI
- Case histories
  - Classification of ARCI applicants and registrants
  - Hong Kong
  - List of sponsors names
- Surveys and programs
  - ARCI registrants status survey, 1965
  - H. Oram report on mission to Hong Kong and Taiwan, 1952
  - F. A. McGuire & J. T. Ivy, Hong Kong - Macao report, 1952
- Immigration - refugee reports and documents, 1952-1965.
  - ARCI charter flights, 1958
  - Refugee Relief Act, 1953
  - Information regarding Presidents' Parole Program, 1962
- Board of Directors meeting minutes, November 21, 1952-May 21, 1969. (Box 2)
- Executive Committee meeting minutes, December 14, 1952-December 8, 1955
- Executive Committee meeting minutes, January 5, 1956-October 1, 1962
- Special minutes, by-laws, charter, February 7, 1952-January 30, 1970 (Box 3)
- Financial statements, corporate members, meeting minutes, March 20, 1953-May 21, 1969
- ARCI - mailings and reports, April 9, 1952-April 20, 1970
- Combined meeting minutes, Executive Directors, Advisory Board, December 12, 1952-May 21, 1969 (Box 4)
- ARCI agendas and reports of the Executive Director, December 12, 1952-May 21, 1969 (Box 5)
- "A" miscellaneous correspondence (Box 6)
- Accounts - Taiwan office
- Accounting department memos
- Advisory Committee on Voluntary Foreign Aid
- Advisory Committee, acceptance of Walter H. Judd invitation, June 3, 1953
- Allman, N. F.
- American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Service, Inc.
- Atterbury, Margaret
- Auditors reports, 1952-1969
- "B" miscellaneous correspondence (Box 7)
- Ballow, Earl
- British government
- Burgess, W. Randolph
- "C" miscellaneous correspondence
- Canaday, Ward F.
- Chambellan, Berger and Welte Company
- Chan, Wellington K.
- Chennault, Claire
- China Club of Seattle, Washington
- China Institute
- Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association
- Chinese government
- Classified lists of ARCI registrants
- Alumni of colleges - contributions (Box 8)
- Compton, Karl - mailings and correspondence
- Congressional support - letters
- Contracts - Hong Kong office.
- "D" miscellaneous correspondence
- Dinner - ARCI, New York, April 28, 1952, with list of dinner sponsors
- Douglas, Paul H.
- Directors
  - Executive Committee
    - Correspondence, 1952-1960
  - Officers
    - Memos
    - Correspondence, general
  - Correspondence
    - Joint Fund Raising Committee
  - Miscellaneous committees
- "E" miscellaneous correspondence (Box 9)
- Edison, Charles
- Emmet, Christopher
- "F" miscellaneous correspondence
- Fairbanks, John A.
- Fire
  - Hong Kong, Christmas 1954
    - Clippings
    - Telegrams
- First National City Bank, New York
- Fitch, Mr. & Mrs. George A.
- Fletcher, Travis
- Foreign Operations Administration
- Free Asia, Committee for (Box 10)
- Freedom Fund
- Freeman, Mansfield
- Frye, Jack
- Fund for Asia
- "G" miscellaneous correspondence
- Gamble, Sidney
- Garside, Bettis A.
- Grace, J. Peter
- Gregerson, Magnus
- Grew, Joseph C.
- "H" miscellaneous correspondence
- Hamilton, Samuel W.
- Han, Lih-wu
- Hausske, Albert J.
- Henry, Robert T.
- Hilton, Conrad N.
- Hornbeck, Stanley K.
- Houghton, Henry S.
- Howard, William J.
- Hu, Shih
- "I" miscellaneous correspondence (Box 11)
- Immigration
- India
- Intergovernmental Committee for European Migration, 1956-1964
- International Cooperation Administration
- International correspondence
- Ivy, James
- "J" miscellaneous correspondence
- Jade Project, 1955
- Judd, Walter H.
- Judd, Walter H. (Box 12)
- "K" miscellaneous correspondence
- Korean War Prisoners release, correspondence, 1952
- "L" miscellaneous correspondence
- Lane, Arthur B.
- Leadership Training Program, ARCI - correspondence
- Le Clercq, Frederick
- Leiper, Henry S.
- Liebman, Marvin
- Little, L. K.
- Luce, Henry
- "Mc" miscellaneous correspondence (Box 13)
- McClure, R. B.
- McKee, Frederick C.
- McNutt, Paul V.
- "M" miscellaneous correspondence
- Marshall, George C.
- Maurer, Herrymon
- Merz, Mrs. Charles
- Moore, Mrs. Maurice T.
- Morris, Newbold
- Moy, Ernest K.
- "N" miscellaneous correspondence
- Nash, Ernest
- National Better Business Bureau
- National City Bank of New York
- National Information Bureau
- New York City - correspondence with various departments
- Nimitz, Chester W.
- North Carolina State Board of Public Welfare
- Northwest Airlines
- Norton, Paul
- "O" miscellaneous correspondence
- Oram, Harold L.
- Overseas Educational Service
- "P" miscellaneous correspondnece (Box 14)
- Pagoda Restaurant, ARCI dinner, June 2, 1952
- Photographs
- Prinie, W. Bruce
- "Q" miscellaneous correspondence
- "R" miscellaneous correspondence
- Reynolds, J. Lewis
- "S" miscellaneous correspondence
- Script - outline for ARCI film
- Severinghaus, Leslie R.
- Smith, C. R.
- Smith, H. Alexander
- Smith, Paul C.
- Smith, Ward D.
- Sockman, Ralph W.
- Special Operations Research, American University, Washington, D.C.
- Sproul, Robert G.
- Stuart, J. Leighton
- Sweatt, Harold W.
- "T" miscellaneous correspondence
- Taylor, George B.
- Tseng, T. C.
- "U" miscellaneous correspondence
- United Europe
- United Nations
- United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees
- U.S. Treasury Department (Box 15)
- U.S. Government, miscellaneous departments
- U.S. State Department
  - U.S. Escapee Program
    - Correspondence
    - Contracts, July 1, 1956 - December 31, 1959
  - Office of Refugees and Migration Affairs
    - Correspondence
    - Contracts, January 1, 1960 - April 28, 1970
- Use of names, ARCI members consent to, 1954-1955 (Box 16)
- "V" miscellaneous correspondence
- "W" miscellaneous correspondence
- Walker, Richard L. - correspondence
- Wang, K. S.
- Wedemeyer, A. C.
- Welch, Herbert
- World Refugee Year, 1959
- Wright, Russell
- "X-Y-Z" miscellaneous correspondence
- Yale in China Association
- ARCI (Box 17)
  - Hong Kong office
    - Reports and minutes, March 12 - Nov. 7, 1952
    - Correspondence
      - 1952
      - 1953 (Box 18)
      - 1954 (Box 19)
      - 1955 - October 8, 1956 (Box 20)
      - 1956 (Box 21)
  - Hong Kong-Taiwan office (Box 22)
    - Correspondence
      - 1957
      - 1958 (Box 23)
      - 1959 (Box 24)
  - Hong Kong office (Box 25)
    - Correspondence
      - 1960-1967
  - Formosa office (Box 26)
    - Correspondence
      - 1952-1953; 1956
  - Taiwan office (Box 27)
    - Correspondence
      - 1954
      - 1956-1956 (Box 28)
  - Registrants (Box 29)
    - Lost contact or deceased
    - Excused from further payments
    - Paid up loans
- Loans to ARCI registrants (Box 30)
  - Au, Duncan B. through Chang, Margaret B.
  - Chang, Eric T. C. through Chen, Franklin Yun Tai (Box 31)
  - Cheng, Allen A. K. through Chou, Chung-Kin (Box 32)
  - Chu, Bing H. through Fung, Tze C. (Box 33)
  - Han, Yu C. through Hu, Shih J. (Box 34)
  - Huang, Allen T. C. through Kwong, Hung L. (Box 35)
  - Lai, Hoi L. through Lee, Sze (Box 36)
  - Lee, Yee B. (Mrs.) through Ling, Nai J. (Box 37)
  - Ling, Charles S. S. through Mao, Julia S. S. (Box 38)
  - Miao, William through Tam, Yang S. (Box 39)
  - Tam, Kei M. through Tung, Theodore C. M. (Box 40)
  - Wai, Kok L. J. (Mrs.) through Wong, Johnson C. S. (Box 41)
  - Wong, Kin Y. through Wu, Peter (Box 42)
  - Wu, Pon T. through Yu, Pon H. (Box 43)
  - Yue, Sing T. through Zung, David S. L. (Box 44)
- Photographs
  - Photo Album #1, ARCI - Hong Kong (Envelopes A-D)
    - 1. Mr. William J. Howard
    - 2. ARCI - Hong Kong Office Staff, 1954
    - 3. Resettlement Section
    - 4. Passage Section
    - 5. Translation Section
    - 6. Accounting Section
    - 7. Secretarial Section
    - 8. Operation Department
    - 9. Dinner party given by ARCI to members of Selection and Recommendation Committee in Hong Kong, 1954 June 1
    - 10. Teacher for Chinese Literature and History
    - 11. Relocation Center - ARCI
    - 12. Mother and Baby - ARCI Relocation Center
    - 13. Refugee cat - She refuses Communist food!!
    - 14. Relocation Center - Staff distributes gifts to children
    - 15. Children waiting for gifts from ARCI
    - 16. Bamboo Home
    - 17. Bundle of clothes contributed by ARCI
    - 18. (No album caption - see back of photograph for caption)
    - 19. Before leaving for U.S.A. under RRA
    - 20. ARCI gave her a ticket to the Health Center for doctors advice on her little girl's fever
    - 21. Refugees work long hours at embroidery to eke out a bare existence
    - 22. All one family of refugees, helped by ARCI
    - 23. Craft worker
    - 24. Parcel gifts distribution by ARCI
    - 25. ARCI - Relocation Center
    - 26. Children with gift packages
    - 27. This group just arrived from Hongkong, came in the same morning to ask for living subsidies and employment from ARCI
    - 28. ARCI cares for a refugee mother whose husband's health has broken under the hardships of existence in Hongkong. Her children have received gifts sent from America.
    - 29. Group investigating housing problem at ARCI
    - 30-31. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 32. Our water buffalo pastures where it can. Roadside in Front of Relocation Center.
    - 33. ARCI donated residences in background
    - 34. ARCI Reg. enjoying life outside of their cottage at ARCI Relocation Center in Taipei
    - 35. A family left for U.S.A. under RRA ARCI applicant
    - 36. Self-help settler from Mainland. Lost 6 children on Mainland suffering from malnutrition.
    - 37. (No album caption - see back of photograph for caption)
    - 38. Indonesian student, ARCI - has sponsored her life story, soon to be published
    - 39. ARCI Teacher Reg. thanks ARCI representative for his residence (in background)
    - 40. Graduate nurse and husband in front of ARCI donated residence
    - 41. Baby 1-1/2 years old. Mother lost her last baby through malnutrition.
    - 42. Only income $200 a month making kiddie clothes for ARCI hand craft products
    - 43. (No album caption - see back of photograph for caption)
    - 44. In front of Recreation Hall renovated by Voice of China. Lo-Seng Leprosarium. Dedication of Recreation Hall.
    - 45. Lo-Seng Leprosarium. Dedication of Recreation Hall renovated by Voice of America. Shows residents.
    - 46. Lo-Seng Leprosarium. Ground-breaking ceremony for new buildings to be constructed with U.S. aid.
    - 47. Ground-breaking and building dedication
    - 48. Ground breaking ceremony and Ambassador & Mrs. Karl A. Rankin
    - 49. ARCI refugee and Taiwan Immigration Officers who carefully checked his papers
    - 50. Prof. Cheng, talking in Employment Office
    - 51. Mr. Fitch presented with banner by 8 ARCI interpreter registrants
    - 52. Little girl doing a Mongolian dance
    - 53. Registrants in furniture shop
    - 54-58. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 59. U.S.A. Ambassador Rankin - Lo-Seng Leprosarium
    - 60. Building donated by ARCI Keelung Hospital
    - 61. Keelung Hospital
    - 62. U.S.A. Consul General - Mr. Kenney
    - U.S.A. Employment Services - Mr. Gerety visits ARCI
    - 63. Our former messenger, now a soldier
    - 64. Farewell to Alice Hiang
    - 65. Registrants making pressure cement and clay brick
    - 66. Cement and clay bricks made by registrants
    - 67. House built by registrants at farm
    - 68. Building houses for registrants on farm. Built by students of Youth Corps during summer vacation.
    - 69. Soldiers of Hospital 3, lined up to receive congratulations and gifts
    - 70. Line up of U.S. cars visiting soldier's hospital No. 3
    - 71. Members of American community joining with women's Anti-Agression League to comfort wounded soldiers
    - 72. Distributing gifts
    - 73-78. Farewell Party to Dr. and Mrs. Fitch. The party was given by twenty members of the Customs service all of whom had been assisted in coming to Taiwan from Hong Kong - several provided with 5 to 12 months living subsidy before the Customs could re-employ them.
    - 79. Residences donated by ARCI at the Yangmingshan Hospital - Ribbon-cutting ceremony
    - 80. Mrs. Fitch making address at Ribbon-cutting
    - 81. Refugees waiting for gifts
    - 82-90. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 91. Leadership Training Group - taken in Hong Kong, at send off party, 1954 August
    - 92. Dr. Fitch and other ARCI staff members together with ARCI leadership Training Students who have just graduated from the Institute of Public Administration. Youth Corps, Taipei, 1954 July
    - 93. Libertyville, Shi-lin-Taipei-Flooded by Typhoon Dina, Sept. 3, 1954. Water rose so rapidly at 9:00 A.M. that the 14 resident families had time to escape with almost none of their belongings. Three women carrying children were nearly drowned on missing the path and stepping into an irrigation ditch. Water reached a height of 3 ft. above the floor but subsided in late afternoon when residents returned. Flooding was almost identical with that caused by Typhoon Wanda on August 1st., except that former occurred at night and residents were rescued by boat.
    - 94. Resettlers a week before Typhoon Wanda
    - 95-97. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 98. Miss Rauch of the U.N. visited Juddville
    - 99. After anti-trachoma and anti-diphteria treatments given at Juddville
    - 100. Some of our primary school students waiting for gifts
    - 101. Colorful gifts of new clothing wrapped in colored towels from Mennonito Mission
    - 102. Mennonito representatives with a Juddville family
    - 103. Distributing Mennonito gifts
    - 104-154. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 155. Mrs. Moore at front office, Juddville
    - 156. Greets a Juddville family
    - 157. Signing name in ARCI Juddville guest book
    - 158. Mrs. Severinghaus signs the guest book
    - 159. Board of Advisers for ARCI luncheon at friends of China Club
    - 160.Visiting refugees' families in ARCI Juddville with Miss D. Whipple
    - 161. Back yards at Juddville
    - 162. Digging foundation for new dormitory
    - 163. Junior citizens meet Mrs. Moore and Mrs. Severinghaus
    - 164. Mrs. Moore inspecting new dormitory
    - 165. Dr. Walter Judd visiting Taiwan. Group of faculty and students together with Dr. Judd and ARCI staff taken on the Youth Corps Academy Campus.
    - 166-173. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 174. In front of refugees' home, Juddville
    - 175. Ambassador and Mrs. Simonson entertained at Juddville. On rear wall, board showing remaining residents in Juddville. Others have gone to new homes. Picture shows model two-family house for faculty residents in schools and colleges employing ARCI registrants.
    - 176. Visiting Juddville
    - 177. Welcomed to Juddville
    - 178. Entertained at Juddville. On rear wall, map showing number and occupation of ARCI registrants all over Taiwan.
    - 179. Juddville office showing residents on board at back
    - 180. Front of temporary quarters of Liberty Rug Factory, 1956 June 21
    - 181-188. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 189. Banners given Taipei Hsien Bldg. Co-op. workers by Tachen for help in constructing their homes, 1956 June 21
    - 190. Co-op, worker at site of Liberty Ramie Rug Factory
    - 191. Two ARCI self-help settlers working at a locally made brick machine
    - 192-202. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 203-208. After Typhoon Wanda
    - 209. Mrs. June B. Devlin of the Psychological Welfare Dept. Pentagon, visited the School of Public Administration
    - 210. Registrants making bricks at Juddville
    - 211. Juddville kiddies - see water buffalo in background
    - 212. Junior Juddville citizens waving Chinese flag
    - 213. Congressman Feigham with Juddville Junior citizens
    - 214. Entrance to Juddville
    - 215. Inspecting Juddville
    - 216. Inspecting Juddville
    - 217. (No album caption - see back of photograph for caption)
    - 218. Primary School
    - 219. Front office of Juddville
    - 220. Mr. Wang of the Central Daily News
    - 221. Miss Evelyn Rauch of WU at Juddville
    - 222. Visiting nurse and doctor from Public Health Center
    - 223. Two babies at Juddville Clinic
    - 224-226. (No album captions - see backs of photographs for captions)
    - 227. Distributing gifts
    - 228. Ribbon-cutting in front of Juddville office
    - 229. Waiting for gifts
    - 230. Tea party
    - 231. Tea party
    - 232. Christmas gift
    - 233. Entrance to Juddville
    - 234. (No album caption - see back of photograph for caption)
    - 235. Interior of a classroom, I-lan Primary School
    - 236. ARCI registrants on faculty of I-lan Middle School
    - 237. Teacher tefugee. One of school rooms where they sleep. I-lan Primary School.
    - 238. Senior students - I-lan
    - 239. Reception at Y.W.C.A.
    - 240. Entrance, Chien Kuo Middle School
    - 241. Lecture by Dr. Atterbury
    - 242. Dr. Fitch delivering speech at ribbon cutting ceremony of ARCI-donated residences at Taoyuan Middle School
    - 243. In doorway of new residence, I-lan Middle School
    - 244. Registrants and guests at I-lan Middle School
    - 245. Boy scouts - I-lan Middle School
    - 246. Inauguration ceremony at I-lan
    - 247. Ready for the ceremony - I-lan Middle School
    - 248. Registrants and principals, I-lan Middle School
    - 249. Senior students - I-lan
    - 250. I-lan main road paved by FOA funds
    - 251. Mr. Hou-An-Tung wife and 4 children in Relocation Center. English teacher at I-lan.
    - 252. This is I-lan Main Streets
    - 253. The proud face of the principal of a Middle School where houses have been built for refugee teachers
    - 254. Ribbon cutting ceremony of ARCI donated residences at Taoyuan Middle School
    - 255. Band played during the ribbon-cutting ceremony
    - 256. Chung Shin Middle School
    - 257. Ribbon-cutting ceremony - opening blocks of faculty residences I-lan Middle School
    - 258. Registrants now teaching in Chung Shin Middle School
    - 259. ARCI staff, teachers and students at Chun Shin Middle School, taken after ribbon cutting ceremony of ARCI residences
    - 260. ARCI staff and whole staff at Chun Shin Middle School
    - 261. Dr. C. Y. Cheng delivering speech at Chung Shin Middle School
    - 262. Mr. C. C. Sheng of ARCI delivering speech at Chung Shin Middle School
    - 263. Palms in courtyard of Chien Kuo Middle School
    - 264. Athletic Field, Chien Kuo Middle School
    - 265. (No album caption - see back of photograph for caption)
    - 266. Taichung Municipal School and the graduating class on commencement day
    - 267. Miaoli School
    - 268. Student band welcoming Messrs. Fitch, Chang and others on the occasion of cutting the ribbon for five teacher residences donated by ARCI to the Miaoli Prov. High School
    - 269. Students listening to speech delivered by Mr. G. A. Fitch at Miaoli Prov. High School on the occasion of cutting the ribbon for five teacher residences donated by ARCI to the School
    - 270. Mrs. Ma Shen-wu and children waiting to receive gift parcels from ARCI staff at ARCI relocation Center
    - 271. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mr. Lan, indispensable, manages all kinds of business.
    - 272. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mr. Mao, accounting.
    - 273. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mr. Yiii famous artist in charge of files.
    - 274. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mr. Tson in charge of files.
    - 275. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mrs. Liang in Dr. Fitch's office.
    - 276. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mr. Su, accounting.
    - 277. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Dr. Cheng, secretary.
    - 278. Some of our ARCI "Team" in our new office. Mr. Sheng, Budget and Student program.
    - 279. Ribbon-cutting ceremony of ARCI donated residences at Chung Shin Middle School, Taipei
    - 280. Dr. Atterbury, Messrs. Sheng & Cheng of ARCI inspecting Chung Shin Middle School grounds accompanied by school authorities
    - 281. Girls class - Kuong Fu School
    - 282. Dr. Cheng of ARCI receiving bouquet from student at Chung Shin Middle School after ribbon-cutting ceremony of ARCI donated residence
    - 283. Miss Atterbury, Messrs. Sheng and Cheng, and Chung Shin Middle School Principal at ribbon-cutting of ARCI donated residences
    - 284. Miss Atterbury receiving bouquet from School girl guide at Chung Shin Middle School after ribbon-cutting ceremony of ARCI donated residence
    - 285. Miss Atterbury at ribbon-cutting ceremony
    - 286. New dormitories, I-lan Middle School
    - 287. Some other I-lan faculty members
    - 288. Mr. Fitch delivering speech at the Changwa Middle School after ribbon cutting ceremony for the five donated residence unit for ARCI registrants teachers (Dr. C. Y. Cheng interpreting)
    - 289. Banner on front gate of Changhwa Middle School welcomes Mr. Fitch, on the occasion of his visit to cut ribbon for the five ARCI donated residences for registrants teachers
    - 290. Mr. Fitch accepting the grateful thanks of Principal Oug of the Changhwa Middle School in front of the plaque indicating ARCI as donor of the five residences
    - 291. Two ARCI registrants, both now teaching at Taoyuan Middle School. Taken in front of their ARCI donated residences.
    - 292. Mr. Liao, Principal of Miaoli Prov. High School, in front of one of the ARCI donated residences
    - 293. Principal Ong's young daughter presents bouquet to Mr. Fitch after ribbon-cutting ceremony at Changhwa Middle School
    - 294. Mr. Fitch cutting ribbon of ARCI donated residences at Taoyuan Middle School
    - 295. Miaoli Prov. High School
    - 296. Mr. Fitch & Cheng of ARCI pose with Changhwa Middle School staff in front of floral arch erected as an expression of appreciation for ARCI assistance
    - 297. Dr. Fitch and Dr. Cheng at the ribbon-cutting ceremony of ARCI donated residences at Taoyuan Middle School